Saroj Sasamal

sarojsasmal@gmail.com Github, LinkedIn

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

I am a Software Engineer at BigBinary with over seven years of experience in full-stack web development. During my career, I have worked with and led various teams, developed applications from scratch, and maintained live applications.

I have ample experience working with JavaScript Technologies and Ruby on Rails. Here are some of my blog posts on Node.js and Vue.js:

- <u>Understanding Async Await In Javascript DEV Community</u>
- Mastering Javascript Promises DEV Community
- Getting Started With Node.js
- <u>Understanding VueJs Computed properties and Watchers</u>

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

Key Skills: React.js, Node.js, Vue.js, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, JavaScript,, Nuxt.js, Python

Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, MariaDB

Tools: Git, Redis, RSpec, Mocha, Chai.js, Jest, IndexedDB, Gatsby.js

WORK EXPERIENCE

BigBinary (April 2021 - Present)

Senior Software Developer

Marriott Learnings (Via BigBinary)

Node.js, React.js, HighChart.js, D3.js, Google Maps API, Litmus, Socket.IO, MongoDB, Postgres

Marriott Learning is a learning platform for JW Marriott hotel employees, where they can enroll themselves into different course programs and certifications via a perfectly designed e-learning platform.

Employees can enroll for functional and leadership roles in a wide range of course categories specifically available for hotel management and related domains like front-office, catering, sales, culinary etc.

- Responsible for managing 5 different applications that interact with the employee's functional and leadership skills-building programs.
- Designed a reporting platform where managers can create on-demand reports with the help of intuitive filters.
- Worked on optimizing the report generation process where large sets of data are processed on a nightly basis to generate reports.
- Developed a notification system using socket lo to facilitate real-time notifications.
- Developed a fully customizable search feature that fetches course contents from in-house DBs integrated with the Oracle API.
- Designed a designated platform for learners to enroll themselves into a new pilot program where a bunch of similar course content is designed and shared with users to learn and track their progress.

Mindfire Solutions (September 2014 – March 2021)

<u>Senior Software Engineer</u>

Ruby on Rails, React.js, Node.js, Vue.js, Dojo, Redis, SocketIO, .NET, Aws Lambda

Aggdata (Via Mindfire)

Node.js, Vue.js, MongoDB, MySQL, Redis, Dojo, React.js, SocketlO

Aggdata provides location data of retail stores and institutions shared across the globe. It scrapes location data from the web and transforms, sanitizes, and summarizes them to provide meaningful information so that it can be consumed by other organizations. This application was a sort of bridge between Jenkins automation server where jobs are configured to run on a scheduled basis to provide location data and the Aggdata data aggregation pipeline

- Responsible for designing and maintaining an application for interacting with Jenkins and keeping track of scraped information.
- Designed a notification system using socketIO to facilitate real-time notifications.
- Responsible for implementing a feature that enables drawing polygons on google maps and storing geo-codes (i.e. latitudes and longitudes) for the retail stores and institutions.

eCurv (via Mindfire)

Node.js, Ejs, MySQL, Redis, Chart.js

eCurv provides IoT-based smart energy demand management software services to optimize your electricity cost. It introduces a new method for electricity distribution through the digital queueing of electric loads.

- While leading a team of 4 developers, I was responsible for designing a graphical interface that would display clients' daily, weekly, and monthly electricity consumption.
- I also worked on building a role management service that grants/limits user roles and permission.

BrandCommand (via Mindfire)

Node.js, Ruby on Rails, MongoDB, PostgreSQL

BrandCommand is a fully customizable multi-tenant web application for product pricing management. It helps distributors to manage the pricing of products based on different attributes like color, size, etc.

- Responsible for implementing Facebook widgets that a customer could embed in their Facebook pages to share them with their friends, and a feature where a distributor can syndicate/send product lines to another distributor so they can revise product lines and modify product prices.
- Designed a custom pricing calculator for implementing base and custom prices for products.
- Designed an interactive dashboard with charts and graphs for sales reports.
- Implemented a chat widget using socket.IO with tawk.to integration for customer support.

Qualitas (via Mindfire)

WebSQL, IndexedDB, AngularJs, HTML Local Storage, Application Cache, Chart.js

Qualitas is an offline web application that preserves appointments and patient information. This helps doctors use their mobile devices -like smartphones and tablets- to download appointments and patient information so they can browse through the patient's records and assess their injuries while they are offline.

• Responsible for designing from start to completion, and maintaining the entire application.

EDUCATION

Institute of Management and Information Technology BPUT (August 2011 – May 2014) *Master in Computer Application.*

Contact Details:

Email ID: sarojsasmal@gmail.com

Mobile No: +919668844755